window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Discrete_Mathematics - Discrete_Mathematics — Slot 9 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Discrete_Mathematics — Slot 9",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Let p,q, r, s represent the following propositions.<br><br>\np:  x\\(\\in\\){8,9,10,11,12} <br>\nq:  x is a composite number <br>\nr:  x is a perfect square <br>\ns:  x is a prime number <br><br>\nThe integer x\\(\\geq\\)2 which satisfies \\(\\neg((p\\Rightarrow q)\\wedge (\\neg r \\vee \\neg s))\\) is ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "11",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39663/gate2016-1-1#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Suppose \\(X_{i}\\) for i =1,2,3 are independent and identically distributed random variables whose probability mass functions are \\(Pr[X_{i}=0]=Pr[X_{i}=1]=1/2\\) for i=1,2,3. Define another random variable \\(Y=X_{1}X_{2}\\oplus X_{3}, \\; where \\; \\oplus\\) denotes XOR. Then<br>\n\\(Pr[Y=0|X_{3}=0]=\\)_______________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "0.75",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8496/gate2015-3-51#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Let R be a relation on the set of ordered pairs of positive integers such that \\(((p,q),(r,s)) \\in R\\) if and only if \\(p-s=q-r\\). Which one of the following is true about R? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Both reflexive and symmetric</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Reflexive but not symmetric</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Not reflexive but symmetric</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither reflexive nor symmetric</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Not reflexive but symmetric</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8500/gate2015-3-50#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>In a room there are only two types of people, namely Type 1 and Type 2. Type 1 people always tell the truth and Type 2 people always lie. You give a fair coin to a person in that room, without knowing which type he is from and tell him to toss it and hide the result from you till you ask for it. Upon asking, the person replies the following <br><br> \"The result of the toss is head if and only if I am telling the truth.\" <br><br> Which of the following options is correct? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>The result is head</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The result is tail</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>If the person is of Type 2, then the result is tail</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>If the person is of Type 1, then the result is tail</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>The result is head</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8427/gate2015-3-16#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>The number of 4 digit numbers having their digits in non-decreasing order (from left to right) constructed by using the digits belonging to the set {1, 2, 3} is____________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "15",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8399/gate2015-3-15#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Suppose U is the power set of the set S={1,2,3,4,5,6}. For any T\\(\\in\\)U, let |T| denote the number of elements in T and T' denote the complement of T. For any T,R\\(\\in\\)U, let T\\R be the set of all elements in T which are not in R. Which one of the following is true? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\forall X\\in U \\; (|X|=|X'|)\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\exists X\\in U \\; \\exists Y\\in U \\; \\) \\((|X|=5,\\; |Y|=5 \\; and \\;  X \\cap  Y=\\phi )\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\forall X\\in U \\; \\forall Y\\in U \\;\\) \\( (|X|=2,\\; |Y|=3 \\; and \\; X \\setminus  Y=\\phi )\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\forall X \\in U \\; \\forall Y\\in U\\; (X \\setminus  Y=Y' \\setminus  X')\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\forall X \\in U \\; \\forall Y\\in U\\; (X \\setminus  Y=Y' \\setminus  X')\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8426/gate2015-3-2#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following well formed formulae is a tautology? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\forall x \\exists yR(x,y)\\leftrightarrow \\exists y\\forall xR(x,y)\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\((\\forall x[\\exists yR(x,y)\\rightarrow S(x,y)])\\rightarrow \\forall x\\exists y S(x,y)\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\([\\forall x\\exists yP(x,y)\\rightarrow R(x,y)]\\leftrightarrow [\\forall x\\exists y(\\neg P(x,y))\\vee R(x,y)]\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\forall x \\forall y P(x,y) \\rightarrow \\forall x\\forall y P(y,x)\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>\\([\\forall x\\exists yP(x,y)\\rightarrow R(x,y)]\\leftrightarrow [\\forall x\\exists y(\\neg P(x,y))\\vee R(x,y)]\\)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8259/gate2015-2-53#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>In a connected graph, a bridge is an edge whose removal disconnects a graph. Which one of the following statements is true? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A tree has no bridges</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>A bridge cannot be part of a simple cycle</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Every edge of a clique with size \\(\\geq\\) 3 is a bridge (A clique is any complete subgraph of a graph)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A graph with bridges cannot have a cycle</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>A bridge cannot be part of a simple cycle</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8252/gate2015-2-52#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>A graph is self-complementary if it is isomorphic to its complement. For all self-complementary graphs on n vertices, n is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A multiple of 4</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Even</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Odd</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Congruent to 0 mod 4, or, 1 mod 4</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Congruent to 0 mod 4, or, 1 mod 4</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8134/gate2015-2-51#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Let X and Y denote the sets containing 2 and 20 distinct objects respectively and F denote the set of all possible functions defined from X to Y. Let f be randomly chosen from F. The probability of f being one-to-one is ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "0.95",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8257/gate2015-2-49#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>The number of onto functions (surjective functions) from set x={1,2,3,4} to set Y={a,b,c} is __________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "36",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8212/gate2015-2-48#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>The number of divisors of 2100 is _____ . <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "36",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8058/gate2015-2-4#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Let R be the relation on the set of positive integers such that aRb if and only if a and b are distinct and have a common divisor other than 1. Which one of the following statements about R is true? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>R is symmetric and reflexive but not transitive</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>R is reflexive but not symmetric and not transitive</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>R is transitive but not reflexive and not symmetric</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>R is symmetric but not reflexive and not transitive</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>R is symmetric but not reflexive and not transitive</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8089/gate2015-2-3#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>The cardinality of the power set of { 0, 1, 2,..., 10 } is _________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "2048",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8092/gate2015-2-2#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following two statements.<br><br>\nS1: If a candidate is known to be corrupt, then he will not be elected <br>\nS2: If a candidate is kind, he will be elected <br><br>\nWhich one of the following statements follows from S1 and S2 as per sound inference rules of logic? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>If a person is known to be corrupt, he is kind</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>If a person is not known to be corrupt, he is not kind</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>If a person is kind, he is not known to be corrupt</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>If a person is not kind, he is not known to be corrupt</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>If a person is kind, he is not known to be corrupt</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8049/gate2015-2-1#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
